gilderlehrman.org 2019-12-16

# Privacy Policy | Gilder Lehrman Institute of American History

### ABOUT THE PRIVACY POLICY STATEMENT

A privacy policy is a legal notice about how organizations use Personal Information collected on a website. It includes information that outlines what data is collected, how it is used, the persons/parties to whom Personal Information may be disclosed, and the security measures taken to protect Personal Information.

This Privacy Policy discloses the privacy practices for the Gilder Lehrman Institute of American History website. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully.

### WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT?

We collect information from you when you register on our site, place an order, or fill out a form.

When ordering or registering on our site, where appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, email address, mailing address, phone number, or credit card information (“Personal Information”). Personal Information does not include data from which you can no longer be identified due to encryption or anonymity.

You may also choose to visit our site anonymously.

### WHAT DO WE USE YOUR INFORMATION FOR?

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:

  * To personalize your experience (Your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs.)
  * To improve our website (We continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you.)
  * To improve customer service (Your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs.)
  * To process transactions (Your information, whether public or private, will not be sold, exchanged, transferred, or given to any other company for any reason whatsoever, without your consent, other than for the express purpose of delivering the purchased product or service requested.)
  * To administer a contest, promotion, survey, or other site feature
  * To send periodic emails (The email address you provide for order processing will only be used to send you information and updates pertaining to your order.)

### Our Legitimate Interests

We process your information given our lawful and legitimate interests in providing the public with access to our programs and membership. We may also process your information given our legitimate interest in undertaking marketing to promote activities and programs to further our mission.

### HOW DO WE PROTECT YOUR INFORMATION?

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your Personal Information when you place an order or enter, submit, or access your Personal Information.

We offer the use of a secure server. All supplied sensitive/credit information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our Payment gateway provider’s database. This information is designed only to be accessible by those authorized with special access rights to such systems. Those authorized are required to keep this information confidential.

After a transaction, your private information (credit cards, social security numbers, financials, etc.) will not be kept on file for more than 30 days.

### DO WE USE COOKIES?

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enable the site’s or service providers’ systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information.

We use cookies to compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

If you prefer, you can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies via your browser settings. Like most websites, if you turn your cookies off, some of our services may not function properly. However, you can still place orders over the telephone.

### DO WE DISCLOSE ANY INFORMATION TO OUTSIDE PARTIES?

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

### THIRD PARTY LINKS

We may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

### CALIFORNIA ONLINE PRIVACY PROTECTION ACT COMPLIANCE

Because we value your privacy we have taken the necessary precautions to be in compliance with the California Online Privacy Protection Act. We therefore will not distribute your Personal Information to outside parties without your consent.

As part of the California Online Privacy Protection Act, all users of our site may make any changes to their information at any time by logging into their control panel and going to the “Edit Profile” page.

### CHILDREN’S ONLINE PRIVACY PROTECTION ACT COMPLIANCE

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act). We do not collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age.

### ONLINE PRIVACY POLICY ONLY

This online privacy policy applies only to information collected through our website and not to information collected offline.

### YOUR CONSENT

By using our site, you consent to our online privacy policy.

### CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page, and/or update the Privacy Policy modification date below.

### FOR USERS IN THE EUROPEAN UNION AND SWITZERLAND

Individuals in the European Union and Switzerland may have certain rights and choices regarding our processing of their Personal Information. Such rights may include the right to (a) know what Personal Information we have collected about you, (b) update or correct such information if you believe there is an inaccuracy, (c) restrict the processing of your Personal Information, (d) request our deletion of your Personal Information, (e) object to our use of your Personal Information, or (g) make a complaint about how we handled your Personal Information.

We reserve the right to verify your identity in connection with any requests regarding Personal Information to help ensure that we provide the information we maintain to the individuals to whom it pertains, and allow only those individuals or their authorized representatives to exercise rights with respect to that information. For questions regarding these rights or the Privacy Policy, or if you would like to exercise any of these rights provided under the law in your jurisdiction, please send us an email at [privacy@gilderlehrman](mailto:privacy@gilderlehrman.org) or call us at 646-366-9666.

We may reject your request, as permitted by applicable law. For example, we may be required by legal, tax, or other reasons to retain certain Personal Information in our business or donation records. If we reject your request, we will notify you of the reason(s) for the rejection.

To the extent provided by applicable law, you may withdraw any consent previously provided to us for our collection of your Personal Information, or object at any time on legitimate grounds, to the processing of your Personal Information. We will apply these preferences going forward. In some circumstances, withdrawing consent to our use or disclosure of your Personal Information will mean that we may no longer be able to provide you with services or information about programming or initiatives that may be of interest to you.

### CHANGES TO YOUR COMMUNICATION PREFERENCES

You may change how we communicate with you (via email or mail) by going to your profile page.

### CONTACT US

If there are any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, you may contact us using the information below.

The Gilder Lehrman Institute of American History  
49 West 45th Street, 2nd Floor  
New York, New York 10036  
United States  
Email: [info@gilderlehrman.org](mailto:info@gilderlehrman.org)  
Phone: 646-366-9666

This page was last updated on January 4, 2019.
